



DESMOND SER

Business Analyst/Consultant with over 7 years experience in large scale system integration projects and UX design. Has project experience in New York, Dubai and Singapore for financial services, automotive, aerospace, retail, government sector and higher education.

WORK EXPERIENCE

12/2023 - Present

Senior Business Analyst

Avepoint

- Leads and provides strategic direction and oversight for a team of 6 business analysts, ensuring the successful delivery of the multi-million project for an education institution for adult learners
- Responsible for coordinating tasks, priorities, and aligning the team's work with client goals and project timeline
- Leading the team in eliciting, documenting, and analysing business requirements. Includes understanding specific needs related to student engagement, curriculum delivery, and technology integration
- Cross collaborating with onsite and remote Developers and Designers for the solution of multiple functional modules and documenting the business processes and functional specifications.

7/2022 - 11/2023

Business Analyst / UX Consultant

Temus

- Implemented a case processing system for Government agency through requirements gathering workshop with key stakeholders and user acceptance testing to ensure a successful deployment
- Conducted design thinking workshops and user interviews for client to understand their customer behaviors and proposed digital solutions

5/2021 - 7/2022

Manager (Digital Services)

Central Provident Fund Board

- Managed important stakeholders and vendor for effective project management and execution
- Designed 2 online services for web and mobile products and validate through usability testing
- Rebranded the mobile app with new logo, animation and user interface using Figma

8/2019 - 5/2021

User Experience Designer

Capgemini - Idean (Rebranded as Frog Design)

- Designed over 500 screens across platforms for Government website through regular user testing
- Implemented design component libraries for large scale projects using Figma and Sketch
- Focused on User-centric design to solve target audience pain points through cross-functional collaboration

8/2018 - 8/2019

User Experience Designer

Synechron Inc

- Designed 3 enterprise solutions and prototyped mobile-responsive designs using Sketch and Invision
- Relocated to and between cities like New Jersey, New York and Dubai for multinational clients based in USA and UAE
- Conducted user research and usability testing for a multinational Dutch bank project

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018

Nanyang Technological University

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours), Information Engineering and Media

2016

National Chiao Tung University

Overseas Exchange Programme, Electronics Engineering and Computer Science

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2022 - 2023

Adjunct Lecturer

CET Academy, Ngee Ann Polytechnic

Conducted user experience design and research lectures for a class of 15 to 20 students

CERTIFICATION & SKILLS

Figma

Product Owner/Manager (POPM)

Balsamiq

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

English - Full Professional Proficiency Mandarin - Native Proficiency

LANGUAGES

CSS PHP **HTML**

SAFe 5 Practitioner

Miro

Visio

Javascript

Sketch

Java

Adobe XD





Photoshop